# 這個廠門口 前兩年我們摘過那個靈芝哦
We picked some, some lingzhi at the entrance of the site, a couple of years ago.
# 野生的靈芝 就在上面一點點
Those were wild lingzhi, just a tiny little bit up there.
# 看下還有沒有現在
Let’s see if there are any now.
# 今人應該有 幾個的話可能有的
There should be some this year, perhaps just a few,
# 多可能沒有
but not more.
# 全是 全是草
All, all are weeds.
# 你看 這有一個
Look! Here’s one,
# 一個那麼小的
such a small one.
# 而且它只長了一個出來
And it’s the only one.
# 誒呀 好新鮮的哦這個
Eya! This one is really fresh, you know.
# 拿回去燉雞 絕對好吃
Let’s take it back and stew with a chicken. Absolutely tasty.
# 去年長了兩三個 今年就長了一個出來
There were a couple of them last year. This year, only one.
# 好啦 帶回去 搞隻雞來燉
Alright. Let’s take it back, fetch a chicken, and then stew it.
# 去看一下
Let’s take a look.
# 天氣還早 我去看一下我家的稻子熟了沒有
It’s still early. Let’s take a look at our paddy field and see if the rice is ripe.
# 我幫忙割稻子啦
I’m gonna help them harvest.
# 現在正在農忙的季節哦
It’s now the farmers’ peak season.
# 不可以偷懶
There’s no reason for slacking off.
# 你看 她們已經割的差不多啦
Look! They’re almost done with the harvest.
# 你看 今年的粮食 大豐收我 看到沒有
Look! The corps this year is Bumper Yield. See?
# 一串都那麼多
There’s so much on just one plant.
# 一顆種能種出
Almost twenty grains,
# 十幾二十顆這樣的來
can be grown from one single seed.
# 產量高了哦
The yield is really high.
# 今天去兄弟家拎了一隻雞回來
I’ve taken a chicken from my buddy.
# 不然太浪費這個靈芝了
Otherwise, this lingzhi would become a big waste.
# 這個靈芝很難找的 好不容易才找到
Lingzhi is really rare. We’ve spent so much effort getting one.
# 要把內臟清理一下 然後再來直接煲
I need to remove the guts, and then I can cook it right away.
# 哇
Wa!
# 這個雞燙 你看
This chicken soup… Look!
# 靈芝哦
It’s lingzhi, not other mushrooms!
# 靈芝蒸出來的雞湯 鮮濃鮮濃的
Soup with lingzhi! Savory and rich!
# 先嘗一下
Let me have a try,
# 味道怎麼樣
and see how it tastes.
# 好燙啊這個
It’s so hot.
# 還缺了一點鹽
I want a bit more salt.
# 嗯 可以啦
Um! It’s alright now.
# 可以吃了 先等一下 好燙啊
We can start now! Not now, it’s very hot.
# 這個靈芝 煲完燙之後就
The lingzhi, after making the soup,
# 沒有 沒甚麼用了
it has, it has already served its purpose.
# 沒甚麼 多大的價值了
It’s no longer, really that worthy now.
# 這個雞腿才是重點
The focus now is this chicken leg.
# 等一下來 等下給個骨頭給你吃
A moment. I’ll leave the bone for you.
# 你看 一叫它們 所有的狗都出來啦
Look! Once I call them, all dogs are coming out.
# 你看 這老母狗 口水都流出來啦
Look! This great mom, is already drooling.
# 你看 這就是以前的胖熊 小胖熊 現在都變樣啦
Look! He is Chubby, Chubby Bear back in those days. He looks completely different now.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright. The video ends here.
# 準備炒點青菜來吃飯
I gotta cook some veggies for our meal.